a lot of people ask me to do calculus in
area so here it is we'll start with the
horizontal line first so let's say we
want to know the area underneath this
line we pick two end points a lower
bound and an upper bound and we want to
find the area underneath our line in
between our two end points this stopped
at the x axis and there's a reason for
that if we want to know what the height
is here it's just going to be our
function value at each of these values
of X the area of this is just a
rectangle which is base time height now
what if we wanted to find the area under
a curve we don't have any formulas from
geometry for this let me use a rectangle
to make an estimation so I set the
height of this one to be the height of
my left bound we can tell this isn't
very accurate it's an underestimate by
quite a bit I can cut it into two pieces
and start using two figures to estimate
it now I've gotten closer this is the
base of our first rectangle this is the
base of our second rectangle this is the
height of our first rectangle and this
will be the height of our second
rectangle our estimate for the area
would be the area of this first
rectangle B1 * H1 plus the area of the
second rectangle B2 * H2 and we can
write this in Sigma notation as b i h i
that way the I can change from 1 to two
we'll start at I equal 1 and we stop at
I equal 2 these are two ways to say the
same thing next let's do four rectangles
here are all the bases and here are all
the heights to add all these up it would
just have four of them or we can change
Sigma notation and make this a four we
could do it again with eight rectangles
which would make eight here or change
this to an eight we do it with 16 which
would add up 16 of these or change our
Sigma notation to a 16 this shows the
advantage of Sigma notation this takes
up way less space than this right here
so let's get rid of all this stuff let's
look closely at the bi if this right
here is base I the left side would then
be x i and this right hand side would be
x sub I + 1 it's one more than this I if
we want to know how big bi is it's the
difference between the two x's and we
call that Delta X let's change this bi
to Delta X so now let's talk about the
height this height hi since this stops
when it hits our function the height is
actually defined by the function value
right there so we would say F of XI so
we can change our hi into F of XI now
let's move this Delta x to the other
side let's change this 16 to n so we can
get any number of rectangles we want and
if we take the limit as n approaches
Infinity we will get closer and closer
to the exact area under that curve we've
come up with new notation for this that
visually mimics that smoothness this
right here gets Rewritten as the
integral symbol which is much more
smooth this f ofx i doesn't make sense
anymore because it's discrete jumps we
want it to be smooth so we're just going
to say f ofx and the Delta X we also
have a smooth way of expressing this as
that distance goes to zero we call it DX
and this is an integral areas are equal
when we do the integral as we chop it
into Infinite pieces we find the exact
area that's the end of this video if you
guys want to learn how to calculate
these integrals please follow me and I
will have more videos coming out you
guys are awesome I'll talk to you soon
bye